socialflow.com 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy - SocialFlow – SocialFlow

## **SOCIALFLOW PRIVACY POLICY**

_Updated: October 10, 2019_

SocialFlow, Inc. (“ **SocialFlow** ”) provides social distribution and monetization solutions for publishers and media companies. We also provide data solutions for researchers and companies interested in trends in online traffic and digital advertising.  SocialFlow provides this privacy policy to inform you how its proprietary technology processes information on behalf of the businesses that use its services. This policy also outlines SocialFlow’s privacy practices on its corporate website, located at <http://www.socialflow.com/> and its Trib.al website located at <http://trib.al/>as well as the types of information we collect from our publisher and advertising customers, which are typically businesses (our “Customers”).

If you are a consumer, you would typically interact with SocialFlow by clicking on a social post published by one of our Customers. See Sections 3b and 3c for an explanation of those interactions. And see Section 1 for a summary of the choices available to you regarding the information we collect and how it gets processed by us.

### **Contents**

  1. Choice Mechanisms
  2. Overview
  3. Different Types of users (“Users”) 
    1.       1. Users Who Visit SocialFlow Sites
      2. Users Who Click on Trib.al Links
      3. Users Who Interact With Social Posts
      4. Personnel of SocialFlow Customers

  * Additional Uses of Information
  * Technology
  * Third-Party Service Providers
  * Retention
  * Security
  * Note Regarding Children
  * Accessing and Updating Personal Data
  * International Data Transfers
  * Changes
  * Contact

### **1.  ** **Choice Mechanisms**

For convenience we are providing opt-out information at the beginning of this privacy policy. To fully understand the definitions and limitations associated with these opt-out provisions, please review the rest of this policy.

**To Do This** | **Take This Action** | **Note / Limitation**  
---|---|---  
Opt out of interest-based advertising powered by other online advertising companies. 

* Where our systems can recognize click data coming from the EU, we don’t collect data.

| Click [http://optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/)

to learn more about interest-based advertising from the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) a self-regulatory organization.

| The opt-out choice will have to be made for each device and browser used, and re-made each time the browsers’ cookies are cleared.  
Opt out of future communications from SocialFlow | Send an email to:  
[opt-out@socialflow.com](mailto:opt-out@socialflow.com) | SocialFlow reserves the right to use SocialFlow User contact information to send important information (such as, for example, information about changes to this Privacy Policy).  
To request to see data stored | Send an email to:  
[forgetme@socialflow.com](mailto:forgetme@socialflow.com) and identify yourself and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed.Or send physical mail to:SocialFlow  
52 Vanderbilt Avenue  
12th Floor  
New York, NY 10017  
Attention: Privacy Group | If sending physical mail please send registered, certified, or priority delivery with tracking information.  
Contact SocialFlow | Send an email to:  
[info@socialflow.com](mailto:info@socialflow.com).Or send physical mail to:SocialFlow  
52 Vanderbilt Avenue  
12th Floor  
New York, NY 10017  
Attention: Privacy Group | If sending physical mail please send registered, certified, or priority delivery with tracking information.  
  
### **2.  ** **Overview**

SocialFlow owns and operates the [SocialFlow](http://www.socialflow.com/) and [Trib.al](http://trib.al/)websites (the “ **Sites”** ). The Sites, together with the content and tools available there, are collectively referred to as the **Services**.  Our Services enable our Customers to post content such as a news story, a picture and/or a video (“SocialFlow Customer Posts”) onto social media platforms such as Twitter and Facebook, and to better understand how such SocialFlow Customer Posts are interacted with by Users (defined below). Individuals, who visit one or both of these Sites or use the Services, by clicking on or otherwise interacting with a link operated by Trib.al, are referred to as **Users**.

This policy explains how SocialFlow may collect, use and disseminate information obtained from Users of the Sites and Services. This Privacy Policy applies to the practices of SocialFlow, and does not apply to other businesses that SocialFlow does not own or control. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any third party services you access.

SocialFlow has identified four primary types of Users, based on how they use the Sites and Services. Note that an individual may fall into more than one category.

  * **Users Who Visit SocialFlow.** These individuals typically visit our Sites to learn more about SocialFlow’s products or services.

  * **Users Who Click on Trib.al Links**. These individuals click on a Trib.al, or Trib.al-managed link to SocialFlow Customer Posts they see in their social feed on a social networking platform like Twitter or Facebook or elsewhere on the internet.

  * **Users Who Interact With Social Posts.** These individuals like, comment, share, or take another social action on  SocialFlow Customer Posts they see inside a social networking platform like Twitter or Facebook.

  * **Employees of SocialFlow Customers.** These individuals use SocialFlow’s Services as part of their job function.

The Collection, Use, and Sharing of information for each of these types of Users are covered in the sections below.

### ****3\. Different Types of Users****

****a.**** **Users Who Visit SocialFlow Sites**

_Collection of Information:_   SocialFlow collects general information about a User’s visit to a website where our Services are enabled (such as, time, date and the URL of the website).  SocialFlow may also collect more specific information about the User and use of the Service, such as demographic data, profile data and frequency or duration of use.Collecting such data (Traffic Data) may entail the use of software programs, cookies, IP addresses or other numeric codes used to identify a computer.

_Use of Information:_   SocialFlow uses this data to help diagnose problems with its web servers, to administer the Site and Services and to analyze User trends and behaviors. User IP addresses are logged for identity verification and automated anti-fraud purposes. SocialFlow may use email addresses gathered from the Sites to communicate pertinent offering updates and announcements to people who have expressed interest in the products via the Sites.

_Sharing of Information:_ We may enable companies to pixel our Sites for advertising and retargeting purposes. Other than that, SocialFlow does not share information with any third party for these Users except for our third-party agents who are contractually required to only use data as directed by SocialFlow.

_EU Countries_ : The legal basis for placing non-necessary cookies and processing pseudonymous cookie IDs is consent upon first visit to the Sites.

_Data Retention_ :  Any contact information shared on an opt-in basis will be retained as long as our business purposes require. Personal data collected from User clicks to our Sites will be retained for two years.

**b. Users Who Click on Trib.al Links**

_Collection of Information:_   SocialFlow collects data from these User clicks onto SocialFlow Customer Posts links including, but not limited to: (i) the full URL of the link, (ii) the User’s IP address (not saved for clicks from the EU) (iii) device settings (browser type, mobile device type, language setting), (iv) the referring website or services (v) the time and date of the click and (vi) a unique identifier placed into our cookies, as described below.

_Use of Information:_   SocialFlow uses Click Data to: (i)monitor and analyze usage and trends of the Sites and Services, (ii)provide the Services to our social publishing Customers to allow them to analyze usage and trends of their content published to social media platforms, and (iii) provide the Services to our data analytics and advertising Customers to allow them to tailor advertising and analyze usage and trends of content published to social media platforms.

_Sharing of Information:_   SocialFlow shares data, including but not limited to, the following with our Customers to understand trends and usage patterns on the Internet: (i) the full URL of the link, (ii) the User’s geolocation data (latitude/longitude, city, state, region and time zone), (iii) device settings (browser type, mobile device type, language setting), (iv) the referring website or services (v) the time and date of the click and (vi) cookies, as described above. We may also associate the unique identifier of our cookie with cookie identifiers of third-party partners for the purpose of enabling targeted advertising for our advertising Customers. This practice, called cookie ID synching, enables those partner’s systems to communicate with SocialFlow’s systems using pseudonymous cookie IDs.

_EU Countries_ : SocialFlow uses IP addresses to ascertain geo-location of User clicks. When those clicks come from Users we believe to be located in the European Economic Area (EEA), we do not set a cookie and we do not share click data with data partners.  Only aggregate click counts and non-identifiable location data are shared with publisher clients for Users located in the EEA.

**c. Users Who Interact With Social Posts**

_Collection of Information:_   Our Services may collect publicly available information about Users that engage with SocialFlow Customer Posts on social networking platforms. For some Customers, we store the visible names or User IDs of Users of social media platforms to display ‘Top Engagers’ of a particular social media post created via the Services.  We also store Retweets and @mentions of Twitter handles for reporting purposes. This information is available to SocialFlow only to the degree allowed by a User’s individual privacy settings with the applicable social media site. If you don’t want your interactions on social media platforms to be public, we encourage you to check the privacy settings of those social media platforms you use.

_Use of Information:_   SocialFlow uses data from Users that interact with  SocialFlow Customer Posts on social media platforms to: (i) allow our publisher Customers to see “Top Engagers” of their Facebook and Twitter handles’ content, and (ii)allow our publisher Customers to see retweets and mentions from Twitter Users

_Sharing of Information:_ For data associated with Users that engage with SocialFlow Customer Posts on social networking platforms, SocialFlow only shares data applicable to each Publisher Customer with that Publisher Customer.

_EU Countries_ : We remove IP addresses and similar digital identifiers from data sets associated with these Users where our systems ascertain that such Users are located in the EEA.

_Data Retention_ : SocialFlow will keep data on these Users who interact with  SocialFlow Customer Posts for up to one year.  Posts that “@mention” a User will be kept for the lifetime of the post as dictated by each social media platform.

**d. Personnel of SocialFlow Customers**

_Collection of Information:_   SocialFlow will collect and store email address, a password, name, phone number, [company name], and certain additional information (such as, for example, preferred contact method) from employees and other personnel of SocialFlow Customers. SocialFlow may also gain access to user access tokens, to give these Users access to their social media platform accounts. These Users may also be required to provide a mobile phone number when they register and login to use the Services for identity verification purposes.

_Use of Information:_   SocialFlow uses this data to deliver the Service, to contact Users when necessary to respond to inquiries for additional information, to provide additional information according to User preferences, and facilitate or process transactions related to the Service. Sometimes this data may be used to send information about products, services, forums and other information and services that are available at the Site. These Users may choose to stop receiving future communications from SocialFlow. SocialFlow will only use a User’s social networking account information for the purpose of providing the Service to a User and will not otherwise attempt to obtain information from (or post information using) such accounts. This information is also necessary to keep the Services secure.

_Sharing of Information:  _SocialFlow may share information with our Customers regarding how each Customers’ personnel utilize and interactive with our Services.

_Data Retention_ : SocialFlow will deactivate accounts after 180 days of non-use, at which time such information may be held in cold storage.

_EU Countries_ :  The legal basis for the processing of personal data about personnel of SocialFlow Customers that are located in the EEA is “contractual necessity.” We process this data in order to provide the Services as specified by contract between that Customer and SocialFlow.

### **4\. Additional Uses of Information**

SocialFlow shares data as described in the “Sharing of Information” sections above. SocialFlow may also disclose personally identifiable data as: (a) reasonably necessary to perform the Service, (b) authorized by a User, (c) otherwise permitted under this Privacy Policy or (d) SocialFlow is required to do so by applicable law or regulation, or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary (i) to conform or comply with any legal, regulatory, law enforcement or similar requirement or investigation, (ii) to protect or defend the rights or property of SocialFlow or any other User or (iii) to enforce the Terms of Service or Primary Agreement.

SocialFlow transfers information to third-party agents (our “Service Providers) who are contractually required to safeguard such information and to use that information only as directed by us.

SocialFlow may be required to disclose your information to third parties when obligated to do so by law and in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected, or actual prohibited activities, including transfer reasonably intended to meet national security or law enforcement requirements, or when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, including but not limited to fraud and situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person.

Finally, SocialFlow may transfer information, including any PII, to a successor entity in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, sale of assets, bankruptcy, or other corporate change. If SocialFlow is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Sites of any change in ownership or uses of your personal data, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal data.

### **5\. Technology**

SocialFlow and our third-party partners use technologies such as cookies, beacon tags and scripts. “Cookies” are pieces of information that a website transfers to a User’s computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Cookies and other tags track User movement on our site and gather behavioral data about our User base for the following purposes: to analyze trends, to administer the Services, and to track Users’ movements around the Services. For information about cookies, please visit <https://www.allaboutcookies.org/>.

SocialFlow cookies also allow us to track when you have clicked on a Trib.al link. Each click of a Trib.al link is tracked using a unique identifier assigned to you in one or more cookies stored by your web browser and associated with Trib.al. We may associate the unique identifier in our cookies with the other information we automatically collect when Users use the Services, as described above, including your location, and SocialFlow Customer Posts you click or otherwise interact with. Users may be able to set their web browser to refuse cookies, which in turn may affect your ability to access and use the Service.

SocialFlow does not use cookies for clicks coming from Users we are able ascertain are located in the EEA, as identified by IP address location.

SocialFlow also uses IP addresses to help diagnose problems with its web servers and administer the Site. IP addresses are also used to provide an audit trail regarding use of the Services.

This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by SocialFlow only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third party services. SocialFlow does not control when or how third parties place cookies on your computer, such as when you visit the website from a Trib.al Link. You can manage other companies’ cookies used for online advertising by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance’s [Consumer Choice Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

### **6\. Third-Party Service Providers**

We may employ and contract with third parties to perform certain tasks on our behalf and under our direction (our “Service Providers”). Our agreements with these Service Providers require that they appropriate safeguard this information and authorize them to use your information only as necessary to provide services to us.

For example, we use Service Providers to host and store data on cloud systems. We also receive IP-based location information from a third-party Service Provider to enable us to infer the location from the IP addresses of computers or devices that visit our Sites or use our Services.

### **7\. Security**

SocialFlow has implemented reasonable security measures to protect the information, both during transmission and once it is received. This includes but is not limited to the use of firewalls and encryption.  Information collected by SocialFlow is stored in secure operating environments that are not made generally available to the public. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or storage device can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while the company strives to use commercially acceptable means to protect your information, it cannot guarantee absolute security.

### **8\. Note Regarding Children**

We do not knowingly collect personal data from children under 16. If we learn that we have collected personal data of a child under 16 (or older as required by applicable law), we will take steps to delete such information from our files as soon as possible.

### **9\. Accessing and Updating Personal Data**

Upon request, SocialFlow will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your information. If you’d like to update, correct, delete, port or deactivate any information provided to us via the Sites or Services, please, email [forgetme@socialflow.com](mailto:forgetme@socialflow.com) and identify yourself and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed. We may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. We will respond to your request to access within a reasonable timeframe. We retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

### **10\. International Data Transfers**

To the extent SocialFlow engages in cross-border data transfers, SocialFlow is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives in accordance with applicable law.

### **11\. Changes**

SocialFlow reserves the right, at its sole discretion, to modify or replace this Privacy Policy, in whole or in part, at any time. From time to time, SocialFlow may amend the terms of this Privacy Policy and will post such changes here.  Continued use of the Service following such notice of any change to the Privacy Policy constitutes your acceptance of those changes.

### **12\. Contact**

For questions regarding this Privacy Policy and/or our privacy practice regarding the Sites or Services, please contact SocialFlow at [info@socialflow.com](mailto:info@socialflow.com), or write to us at:

SocialFlow, Inc.  
52 Vanderbilt Avenue  
12th Floor  
New York, NY 10017
